FESTUS MACHARIA

IT Officer

Address Nairobi Kenya

Phone +254712789685

Email festusgakure@gmial.com

Technology-inclined professional possesses strong troubleshooting capabilities and customer-oriented attitude. Experienced in providing network and software support to users and developing and implementing technical solutions. Adept at analyzing system performance and security to derive optimal user experience.

Competencies

Peripheral repair and maintenance

Help Desk Operations

Desktop Technical Support

Wireless Networking

Software deployment management

Applications installations

Work History

2022-07 - current IT Technician

Deities Technologies, Nairobi

- Configuration and installation of KRA TIMS devices
- Integrating ESDs with invoicing systems for them to sign and transmit to TIMS
- Respond to support requests from end-user and patiently walk individuals through basic troubleshooting tasks of ETRs.
- Explain technical information in clear terms to non-technical individuals to promote better understanding.
- Correct connectivity faults to restore access to local networks and public web.
- Installation and configuration of Deitax POS to invoicing systems for fiscalization of invoices using PDF capture and API for seamless transmission to eTIMS.

2021-09 - 2021-12 IT Intern

Gatamathi Water and Sanitation Company, Muranga

- Collaborate to assist support protocol development and offered consultation based on cross-functional knowledge.
- Assisted IT members by crafting project research material for implementation.
- Delivered assistance and support tem-based IT projects.
- Supported IT department in handling technology rollout and maintenance.

Education

2018-09 to 2022-10: Chuka University

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

2013-01 to 2017-11: Chinga Boys High School

KCSE

Certificate – (Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education)

2006-01 to 2013-11: Kirimahiga Primary School

KCPE

Certificate – (Kenya Certificate of Primary Education)